<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://geckoboard.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://geckoboard.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-05T22:40:09+00:00</updated><id>http://geckoboard.com/</id><title type="html">Geckoboard</title><subtitle>Use Geckoboard to build clear, effective data dashboards for your business that keep teams informed, motivated and aligned around your KPIs. Try for free.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">7 tech founders lift the lid on how they set hello</title><link href="http://geckoboard.com/blog/7-tech-founders-lift-the-lid-on-how-they-set-goals/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 tech founders lift the lid on how they set hello" /><published>2017-06-02T17:06:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-02T17:06:00+00:00</updated><id>http://geckoboard.com/blog/7-tech-founders-lift-the-lid-on-how-they-set-goals</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://geckoboard.com/blog/7-tech-founders-lift-the-lid-on-how-they-set-goals/">&lt;p&gt;We believe the best insights for scaling a company come from other founders who have or are currently in the process of scaling their business. To tap into their insights and experience, we interview founders and CEOs on their toughest challenges for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/topics/secrets-for-scaling/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Secrets for Scaling podcast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(To be notified when the latest episodes are available, subscribe to Secrets for Scaling on &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/geckoboard&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/secrets-for-scaling/id1178675789?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve talked to dozens of founders, it’s become clear there’s no one-size-fits-all approach to goal setting. What works for one company might be a disaster for another. The ideal framework seems to vary based on the culture and values of the business, but many founders succeed by stealing the best parts from other companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’ve compiled several goal setting approaches from founders with different team structures, sizes, and cultures. We hope the following insights provide you with ideas or a foundation to test your own goal-setting frameworks and strategies. 
##Setting goals for fully autonomous teams
####Ratio, 19 people
Currently with 19 team members, collaboration happens naturally at Ratio due to their loose team structure. Even the people with operational roles are constantly working on how to automate their tasks so they can focus on more interesting things. No one person has all the skills needed to tackle any one project alone, so collaboration is critical to move projects forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-ratio-marc-biles/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Marc Biles&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; founder and CEO of Ratio, spends up to two months every year updating the company’s annual business plan. During that process, he comes up with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/okrs-objectives-and-key-results/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OKRs (objectives and key results)&lt;/a&gt; for the quarter. These OKRs for the company as a whole cascade down through the team, with each team choosing their own quarterly objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marc oversees this process to ensure they fit into the larger business objectives and vision over the next 12 months. He gently nudges the different teams during the goal-setting process to ensure all team objectives still align with the overall company objectives. &lt;em&gt;“The key thing is to keep the objectives simple,”&lt;/em&gt; Marc shares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their main objective is to grow and extend the margins across the group. It’s easy to cascade those big, overarching objectives down into teams and individuals because they’re simple to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Want to learn more? Listen to the entire &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-ratio-marc-biles/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ratio podcast&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;
####Makers Academy, 24 people
Makers Academy also has a loose structure where their team of 24 self-organize around tasks. They work together to identify who’s best to make the decisions, who’s best to lead a certain effort, and who’s best to help. This hierarchy changes with each task. Co-founder and CEO &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-makers-academy-evgeny-shadchnev-podcast/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Evgeny Shadchnev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; says it’s a very natural and ad hoc process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To allow for such autonomy, they build their team based on trust, not on fear. Evgeny saw so many practices in modern companies being built on fear and didn’t want to replicate them. Makers Academy starts with the premise that every team member is trusted to do what’s best for the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were curious how far they could push that ideology. The result is a team who decides what they work on, how they work on it, and how much they’re compensated for it (learn more about their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-makers-academy-evgeny-shadchnev-podcast/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;self-setting salaries here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of setting a revenue goal for the end of the year, for example, they organize themselves around the mission of the company by asking &lt;em&gt;“What is the purpose of the company?”&lt;/em&gt; followed by &lt;em&gt;“What can we do today to push us closer to that point?”&lt;/em&gt; Because everyone is trying to do what’s best for the company, even if a strategy or test fails, it self-corrects and works out for the best in the long run. That’s why Evgeny suggests focusing on the long term and hiring people who have bought into that vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, it looks like a lot of self-organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Listen to the entire &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-makers-academy-evgeny-shadchnev-podcast/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Makers Academy podcast&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;
####Verdigris, 24 people
Co-founder and CEO &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-verdigris-mark-chung/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mark Chung&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and one of his co-founders, Thomas, came from a functionally structured company where each person had a specific skill and function. They found this to be a poor way to facilitate collaboration. They experimented with making roles more cross-functional so that more people with overlapping skill sets were collaborating on the same team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They then found themselves needing a designated role to manage those cross-functional teams. They didn’t want to reintroduce management structure so they created the elected team structure instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All teams at Verdigris operate with the same agile paradigm working in sprints, including Marketing and Sales. The elected representative for each team serves a hybrid product owner and scrum master with the responsibility to manage a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pivotal.io/tracker&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pivotal board&lt;/a&gt; where they prioritize the tasks at hand on a sprint-by-sprint basis. They also communicate the needs for that sprint to their team and facilitate the sprint. Each representative rotates out every two quarters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;blog-newsletter-signup inside&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;newsletter-signup-head&quot;&gt;Can we send you a short bi-weekly email with lessons learned from other founders scaling their business?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;form action=&quot;//geckoboard.us1.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=f8c11c17753d5c653c8d22b3d&amp;amp;id=d7a449ccce&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; id=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&quot; name=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&quot; class=&quot;validate form-wrapper&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; novalidate=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;email&quot; value=&quot;&quot; name=&quot;EMAIL&quot; class=&quot;required email&quot; placeholder=&quot;Your Email Address&quot; id=&quot;mce-EMAIL&quot; /&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Subscribe&quot; name=&quot;subscribe&quot; id=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe&quot; class=&quot;button&quot; /&gt;&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founding team meets annually to define a set of objectives around what they want to accomplish and how they’ll measure success for the year, keeping the plan loose to leave room for team innovation. But even a loose plan needs clarity. Like many of the companies we talk to, the entire Verdigris team meets once every quarter to decide what they want the company to look like for the next quarter, what their goals are, and what metrics they’ll use to measure them. During this time, they set OKRs for every team and individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Listen to the entire &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-verdigris-mark-chung/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Verdigris podcast&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;
##Setting goals for core teams
####Vinyl Me Please, 15 people
At Vinyl Me Please - a monthly subscription record company with 15 team members, different teams own areas of the business with each member owning their own tasks. The entire team then gets together every two weeks to report progress, give ideas, and share how they can help each other. The leadership team re-shares their vision, goals, and progress against those goals. They encourage areas of the business that aren’t moving as fast as they’d like and celebrate those that are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To set goals, co-founder &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-tyler-barstow-vinyl-me-please-podcast/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tyler Barstow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; outlined what they wanted to be as a company in practical terms. The leadership team asked themselves and the team: &lt;em&gt;“what does the best damn record club ever look like?”&lt;/em&gt; Then asked, &lt;em&gt;“what does support, content, marketing, etc. look like for the best record club?”&lt;/em&gt; Those answers end up being their goals for the year or quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They then arrange those goals in a way that makes people accountable to accomplish them and feel free to shift direction as they’re learning along the way. They try to get from the abstract to the tangible as quickly as possible. They create timelines and structure around the practical goals mentioned above so they can answer the questions, &lt;em&gt;“was this a good idea or no?”&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;“what returns is this idea getting us?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Listen to the entire &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-tyler-barstow-vinyl-me-please-podcast/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vinyl Me Please podcast&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;
####Marvel, 31 people
With 31 employees, Marvel has recently broken their team out into the core departments needed. Each team has its own mini-culture and way of working, with a leader assigned to each. Co-founder &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-marvel-murat-mutlu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Murat Mutlu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and the leadership team leave choosing the best tools, processes, and collaboration techniques up to the teams and their leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At their current stage, Marvel uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/learn/what-is-a-key-performance-indicator-kpi/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;KPIs (key performance indicators)&lt;/a&gt; to keep the team aligned as the company grows. They’ve found it most effective to have each team focused on one or two core things at a time, then move onto the next. Murat knows they’ll eventually need to roll out KPIs at the individual level. But for now, they’ve found that the team self-assigns responsibility well, as long as they know their focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Listen to the entire &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-marvel-murat-mutlu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Marvel podcast&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;
####Segment, 130 people
In the early days, with 20-30 employees, Segment had a wild west approach to goals where everyone did what they had to do to take the company to the next level. As they reached 50-60 employees, co-founder and CEO &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-peter-reinhardt-segment/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Peter Reinhardt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; realized they needed more structure around goals. The team needed context behind what they were working on and began taking a collaborative approach to setting yearly goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now at 130 team members, they’ve gotten better at setting goals around what they want to accomplish, then orienting their team around those goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter drafts the annual plan, completing about 60% of it. Then the executive team gives feedback contributing about 20% until they get it to 80% complete. They then share it with the rest of the team who shares their feedback and collaborates with their executive team member to work on their goals and activities quarter by quarter until the plan is 100% complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modeled after the example of SpaceX, Peter takes a mission to metrics approach for structuring and organizing the Segment team. Everyone understands the breakdown of the final mission (for SpaceX it’s to go to Mars) down to the things they’re contributing to (e.g. if they’re successful landing then the designing of gimbals on a rocket engine was successful).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important element of goal-setting at Segment is writing the goals and processes down. Peter says that as managers with concrete deliverables, it’s easy for things like goal-setting or decision processes to become ingrained culturally and not written down. But to be effective, managers need to be held accountable. And to be held accountable, goals and processes need to be recorded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Listen to the entire &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-peter-reinhardt-segment/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Segment podcast&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;
##Setting goals for a larger, flat hierarchy with team managers
####FareHarbor, 135 people
Beyond team managers at FareHarbor, the rest of the company is structured as a flat hierarchy. Now with over 135 people, there’s an expectation that everyone is working towards the common goal of improving the customer experience and managers are working together to make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Co-founder and CEO &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-fareharbor-lawrence-hester/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lawrence Hester&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; uses KPIs to help everyone move towards the same goal and believes in keeping their KPIs flexible. While there might be the one goal the company is continuously working towards, what teams and individual people are working on constantly changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because each team has slightly different goals, they re-evaluate how KPIs move the organization forward about once per month. FareHarbor’s leadership explains to the team that although they set KPIs, if the metrics aren’t driving the business forward or helping the team grow professionally, they’re going to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Listen to the entire &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-fareharbor-lawrence-hester/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FareHarbor podcast&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Finding what works for your company
When it comes to setting goals, each company has their own unique approach. Hopefully, the examples we’ve looked at in this post will help spark ideas for what might work best at your company depending on your team structure and culture.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We believe the best insights for scaling a company come from other founders who have or are currently in the process of scaling their business. To tap into their insights and experience, we interview founders and CEOs on their toughest challenges for our Secrets for Scaling podcast.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unbounce’s Oli Gardner on evolving metrics, scaling culture, AI, and more [Podcast]</title><link href="http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-unbounce-oli-gardner-podcast/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unbounce’s Oli Gardner on evolving metrics, scaling culture, AI, and more [Podcast]" /><published>2017-05-30T08:17:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-30T08:17:00+00:00</updated><id>http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-unbounce-oli-gardner-podcast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-unbounce-oli-gardner-podcast/">&lt;p&gt;In this episode of Secrets for Scaling, we chatted with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/oligardner&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Oli Gardner&lt;/a&gt;, Co-Founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://unbounce.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Unbounce&lt;/a&gt; - a landing page and conversion marketing platform. The software allows marketers to quickly create, launch, and test high-converting landing pages and website overlays without developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based in Vancouver, BC, Unbounce has helped marketers and digital agencies increase website and campaign conversions since 2009. They’re currently investing heavily in machine learning and artificial intelligence (AI) in their move towards becoming a conversion automation platform. Here’s what they look like today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Founder experience: &lt;em&gt;8 years&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team size: &lt;em&gt;180 team members&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customers / Revenue: &lt;em&gt;$17 million in ARR&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company founded: &lt;em&gt;2009 (almost 8 years old)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Business model: &lt;em&gt;SaaS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oli talked to us about the future of AI and machine learning in marketing, the top mistakes he sees founders make, the early marketing decisions that led to their success today, and more. Listen to the full episode below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/325202004&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Like this episode? To be notified when the latest episodes are available, subscribe to Secrets for Scaling on &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/geckoboard&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/secrets-for-scaling/id1178675789?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Episode highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be a pioneer in an awareness channel&lt;/strong&gt;. Unbounce was a pioneer in content marketing in 2009. They blogged a ton about landing pages and leveraged larger communities and popular blogs. By creating a giant piece of valuable content on the Moz blog, Oli positioned himself and Unbounce as a market leader soon after launch. If you want to make a splash, go big and go different from everyone else, especially when experimenting with new channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose smart integration partners for early growth&lt;/strong&gt;. Unbounce looked at every marketing technology platform they could logically integrate with, such as CRMs and email marketing software. They used Alexa and compete.com to see which had 4x, 10x their traffic. They then focused on building relationships with those with a high level of potential growth, added value for their customers, and alignment with their value system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hire people who will create or influence the culture and values you want to see&lt;/strong&gt;. Oli says much of their early success was due to hiring amazing people. And because they hired customer support people who truly care about their customers and product, they score a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/learn/kpi-examples/marketing-kpis/net-promoter-score-nps/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Net Promoter Score&lt;/a&gt; (NPS) of 90 – higher than Apple’s!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use your application process to filter out the people who don’t care&lt;/strong&gt;. Unbounce tears up any resumes. Instead, they ask candidates to create landing pages explaining why they want to work for Unbounce and why they should be hired. This filters out people who don’t care about who they work for and are applying in mass. It also means they have to get into the product and engage with early touchpoints with the brand. And it allows the most creative candidates to stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your metrics have to evolve&lt;/strong&gt;. In the first few years, Unbounce focused on new trial starts (NTS) - people who sign up for a trial with their credit card info. Oli says “but that has to evolve.” No matter what metric they’re focused on for whatever phase they’re in, their goal has always been to focus on the lifetime value of a customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyze behavior to design a product for your ideal customers&lt;/strong&gt;. Oli says, “It’s more than just numbers, it’s the who behind those numbers - who are they and what do they need to be successful?” That’s why Unbounce analyzes the behavioral data behind their customers with the highest LTV. Their findings often relate to the integrations they’re using. If their highest value customers are using their Salesforce integration, they highlight that in their marketing to attract similar customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price for your ideal customers&lt;/strong&gt;. Unbounce has done away with their lowest pricing tier three times. Perception is important, and they’ve had enterprise companies tell them that their product was “too cheap.” The result of focusing on their more expensive plans is a customer base with higher value and greater retention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your core values will drive employee behavior&lt;/strong&gt;. Unbounce’s core value system keeps the team aligned with their vision. And the structure helps them make smarter decisions. For example, because one of the company’s core values is to be bold, team members are more comfortable doing something that might be a bit risky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send employment engagement surveys and pay attention to the results&lt;/strong&gt;. Unbounce sends employee surveys every six months. They don’t just analyze the results, they take action on them. This is a big part of being a people-centric company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build your core values into your algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;. Oli says that one of the most interesting components of AI and machine learning will be the ability to program your core values into the system. So if a bot is answering your customer support inquiries, you can incorporate delight into its messages, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authenticity can suffer as you scale&lt;/strong&gt;. Oli says this is especially true on social media and in customer communications. He added, “Remember that if you have that connection with your customers, then you lose it, you’re letting people down. They’re going to go to your competitors because it feels like you’re putting money before people. And that’s not the right way to do it; one takes care of the other.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t just listen to your customers, make change&lt;/strong&gt;. To help maintain their authenticity, Unbounce has an experts community group who they meet with via video every two weeks. They listen to their feedback and drive decisions in the direction of their most ideal customers’ needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have an advisory board to keep you in check&lt;/strong&gt;. Another way to maintain your authenticity is to ask for help and advice through others who have been through it. Oli recommends an advisory board and bringing on senior leadership sooner rather than later. He added, “Having those sounding boards and those people X years ahead of you on a similar journey can avoid a lot of mistakes just by answering questions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the 75-person mark, scale your leadership team before mass hiring&lt;/strong&gt;. At 75 people, you might think hiring a bunch of people will help, but it won’t. Oli says you have to get your leadership team in place or else it will become unmanageable. “If you’re going fast, the amount of people you have to onboard takes away from people trying to do the actual work. If you don’t have enough people in management, it’s going to suck up your time, which isn’t beneficial to anyone.” He advises, “reach out to three founders of similar businesses - ask for help and really really pay close attention to what they say.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you been enjoying episodes of S4S? We’d appreciate a &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/secrets-for-scaling/id1178675789?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;review on iTunes&lt;/a&gt;. It only takes a minute. Cheers!&lt;/em&gt; ✌&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In this episode of Secrets for Scaling, we chatted with Oli Gardner, Co-Founder of Unbounce - a landing page and conversion marketing platform. The software allows marketers to quickly create, launch, and test high-converting landing pages and website overlays without developers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to avoid the most common mistakes in dashboard design</title><link href="http://geckoboard.com/blog/how-to-avoid-the-most-common-dashboard-design-mistakes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to avoid the most common mistakes in dashboard design" /><published>2017-05-25T15:54:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-25T15:54:00+00:00</updated><id>http://geckoboard.com/blog/how-to-avoid-the-most-common-dashboard-design-mistakes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://geckoboard.com/blog/how-to-avoid-the-most-common-dashboard-design-mistakes/">&lt;p&gt;Designing a TV dashboard is an evolution with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/build-better-dashboards-by-iterating/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;many iterations&lt;/a&gt; as you adjust the metrics and goals to what’s most relevant for your growing company. It’s a learning process that, like most things, is rare to get just right the first time. But thanks to the lessons of other experienced dashboarders, it’s possible to avoid the most common dashboard design mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll take a look at what these mistakes are along with practical advice for building beautiful and effective dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Mistake 1: Displaying too many metrics
When displaying a dashboard on a TV there’s a hard limit on how much information will fit. A TV dashboard has limited real estate. While there isn’t an exact maximum number of visualizations or metrics, bear in mind that every additional metric you add detracts emphasis from what’s already there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be as ruthless as you can. Ask yourself: Does this metric &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need to be on the dashboard? Does this metric trigger action?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When it comes to building a dashboard, less is more. Just try to pick a few things that have an impact on the business and then focus on the actions that improve the values. It’s a focus thing. When you have less information, it’s a signal to your team that these are actually the important values for our business.” - Niklas Slotte, Founder and CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://sayduck.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sayduck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CEO of Komet Sales, Alejandro Perez, came up with an incredibly vivid illustration to help evaluate exactly which metrics to put on his dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Imagine if every 1x1 visualization is going to cost you a hundred bucks. Which ones will you put on the dashboard? You’ll be much more selective. My mistake when I got started was to get excited and think, “I’ve got all this real estate - I’ve got to fill it up!” But that just creates confusion because as people look at the dashboard they see all these metrics, all these different things and they go nuts. It’s much better to start small and build up the number of metrics slowly.” - Alejandro Perez, CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kometsales.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Komet Sales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve determined that each metric is truly essential but the dashboard is still crowded, consider splitting the data into separate dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Mistake 2: Randomly positioned metrics and lack of hierarchy
As with any other piece of real estate, making efficient use of space is important. This is especially true when it comes to the location and hierarchy of your metrics on a TV dashboard. By hierarchy, we’re referring to the size and prominence of a visualization - the larger the visualization and the closer it is to the top/left, the greater the prominence or emphasis it will have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to location, both the actual (top-left, middle, bottom-right, etc.) and relative (metric groupings) location of visualizations matter. Because we read left to right, top to bottom in the Western world, the most valuable space on a dashboard is the top-left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are your metrics stuck in the same (random) order that you added them to the dashboard? Is your most important information buried in the middle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid the chaos of randomly positioned metrics by prioritizing the data in order of importance. Then adjust the size and location of your most critical metrics so they’re larger than the rest and positioned towards the top-left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/ecommerce-dashboard-hierarchy.png&quot; alt=&quot;example-ecommerce-dashboard&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Example &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/learn/dashboard-examples/ecommerce-dashboard-example/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ecommerce Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; with the most important metric larger and positioned top-left.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another handy tip for combatting a random layout is to group metrics related to the same thing together. Or if you have the same metric for different things (i.e. trial conversion rate and customer conversion rate), group those together. This makes it easier for a viewer to find what they’re interested in seeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/adwords-dashboard-grouping.png&quot; alt=&quot;example-adwords-dashboard&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Example &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/learn/dashboard-examples/adwords-marketing-dashboard-example/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adwords Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; with related metrics grouped together.&lt;/em&gt;
##Mistake 3: Using unclear titles
Titles might seem like an afterthought when building a dashboard, but they’re actually a critical part in conveying your data clearly. Having the right metrics on your dashboard isn’t very useful if people don’t know what the metrics are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid this common mistake by using pithy and consistent visualization titles that make it easy for people to understand the metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The titles on your dashboard must have meaning so people can quickly understand what the metrics are. Keep the title true to the metrics. Don’t just call it ‘Tickets’, call it ‘Tickets on mobile platform today’. Titles can make all the difference in making a dashboard useful and understandable.” - Lucas Pereira Lima, Business Intelligence Developer at &lt;a href=&quot;http://clickbus.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Clickbus.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also minimize title repetition by grouping similar metrics together (as mentioned and shown above).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Mistake 4: Different visualizations, just because
One of the most common misconceptions about building a dashboard is that you need lots of different visualizations in order to make it more exciting. It’s tempting to use a bar chart just because you’ve already got a couple of line charts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Dashboards are not an appropriate venue for artistic impression.” - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.perceptualedge.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stephen Few&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resist this temptation. Superficially, the dashboard might look more interesting, but variety for the sake of variety isn’t actually helpful for clearly communicating data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be true to your metric and use the visualization that’s most appropriate. &lt;em&gt;(Not sure what is appropriate for the metrics you have? Take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/best-way-visualize-data-handy-flowchart/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this handy flowchart for choosing the best visualization&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, simple is always better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Mistake 5: Unnecessary elements with or around the data
Unnecessary color, text, images, or other decoration on a dashboard is distracting at best and at worst makes the data illegible. (A whole article could be devoted to elegant and efficient data visualizations, but for this post a quick overview will suffice.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technical term for extraneous elements on a dashboard is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infovis-wiki.net/index.php/Data-Ink_Ratio&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;data-ink ratio&lt;/a&gt;. Ideally, a dashboard should have the minimum amount of ink (this could be text, color, images, textures, etc.) required to clearly display the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means avoiding unnecessary decorations and removing anything on your dashboard that doesn’t have a purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good practice to keep your dashboard clean is to periodically take inventory of everything that’s displayed by asking the question: &lt;em&gt;“What purpose does this have?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Summary: Establish good dashboarding habits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treat your dashboard like high-value real estate by displaying only essential metrics that inspire action.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Group similar metrics together and create an obvious hierarchy for your most important metrics by using size (larger = more important) and position (top-left = highest priority).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use pithy and consistent visualization titles so all viewers understand what the metrics are.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/best-way-visualize-data-handy-flowchart/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;most appropriate visualization for your data&lt;/a&gt;, even if that means less variety.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove unnecessary distractions and decorations from your dashboard. Only keep the elements that serve a (useful) purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=”typeform-widget” data-url=”https://simon406.typeform.com/to/SQuPNr” data-transparency=”100” data-hide-headers=true data-hide-footer=true style=”width: 100%; height: 450px;” &amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &lt;script&gt; (function() { var qs,js,q,s,d=document, gi=d.getElementById, ce=d.createElement, gt=d.getElementsByTagName, id=&quot;typef_orm&quot;, b=&quot;https://embed.typeform.com/&quot;; if(!gi.call(d,id)) { js=ce.call(d,&quot;script&quot;); js.id=id; js.src=b+&quot;embed.js&quot;; q=gt.call(d,&quot;script&quot;)[0]; q.parentNode.insertBefore(js,q) } })() &lt;/script&gt; &amp;lt;div style=&quot;font-family: Sans-Serif;font-size: 12px;color: #999;opacity: 0.5; padding-top: 5px;&quot; &amp;gt; powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typeform.com/examples/?utm_campaign=SQuPNr&amp;amp;utm_source=typeform.com-8113383-Pro&amp;amp;utm_medium=typeform&amp;amp;utm_content=typeform-embedded-poweredbytypeform&amp;amp;utm_term=EN&quot; style=&quot;color: #999&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Typeform&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Designing a TV dashboard is an evolution with many iterations as you adjust the metrics and goals to what’s most relevant for your growing company. It’s a learning process that, like most things, is rare to get just right the first time. But thanks to the lessons of other experienced dashboarders, it’s possible to avoid the most common dashboard design mistakes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vanity metrics on your dashboard: Are they always so bad?</title><link href="http://geckoboard.com/blog/vanity-metrics-on-your-dashboard-are-they-always-so-bad/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vanity metrics on your dashboard: Are they always so bad?" /><published>2017-05-17T13:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-17T13:55:00+00:00</updated><id>http://geckoboard.com/blog/vanity-metrics-on-your-dashboard-are-they-always-so-bad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://geckoboard.com/blog/vanity-metrics-on-your-dashboard-are-they-always-so-bad/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Vanity metrics are dangerous.” - &lt;a href=&quot;http://theleanstartup.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eric Ries, The Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is certainly a lot of truth to this statement but what if I told you it’s not that black and white? What if I told you that in some cases, sharing vanity metrics with your team isn’t that bad?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shut the front door!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what if I told you that vanity metrics can sometimes actually be used for good?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shut every door in the house!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than just make shocking statements, let me explain from the beginning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##What is a vanity metric?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanity metrics are feel-good data – they’ll make you all warm and fuzzy inside, but they don’t directly help you make decisions that will affect anything meaningful in your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They tend to be absolute numbers with little context or sense of causality. If you’re looking at a metric and you see it change over time, but you can’t easily figure out why it’s changed or what you can do to impact it directly, then you’ve probably got a vanity metric on your hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total customers&lt;/strong&gt; – This number will almost always increase over time. Without supporting metrics to show how much your customers are spending, how long they stay customers for and how much it cost to acquire them, focusing on this metric alone is unlikely to be valuable in and of itself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Downloads&lt;/strong&gt; – A mobile app could get millions of downloads, but does anyone actually use it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of Twitter followers&lt;/strong&gt; – You could have hundreds of thousands, but are they really engaged with your brand?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time on site&lt;/strong&gt; – What does this actually mean? Looking at this alone, there’s little indication of how increasing time on site creates actual business value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are of course exceptions when it might make sense to look at these, and often it’s circumstances specific to your business that can determine whether a metric is a vanity metric or not. That’s why being able to identify a vanity metric is an important skill that’s worth refining over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Vanity has some value, but now we’re always pushing to make our metrics immediately actionable. Big numbers like overall organic traffic were useful to look at when we were smaller, but as we’ve grown as a company we have become a lot better at knowing what’s actually important. Now we’re focused on much more granular metrics like organic traffic by week and organic traffic by page type.” - Mark Myers, Co-Founder and Chief Design Officer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.g2crowd.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;G2 Crowd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least Mark wasn’t focusing on clicks…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aH41_Dc0yQk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##What is an actionable metric?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If vanity metrics are unhelpful and fail to drive business value, actionable metrics are much more likely to enable you to spot trends, realize problems, and help you make decisions that help you achieve your goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a savvy manager might take the vanity metrics above and break them down into metrics that the team can actually impact with their work day-to-day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Average order value&lt;/strong&gt; instead of &lt;strong&gt;total customers&lt;/strong&gt; –  Understanding and monitoring the revenue generated by specific types of buyer will better inform you of where opportunities to optimize exist or where money is being left on the table.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly Active Users&lt;/strong&gt; instead of &lt;strong&gt;Downloads&lt;/strong&gt; – Understanding how many downloaders of your app actually continue to use it is much more useful for understanding engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CTR of social posts&lt;/strong&gt; instead of &lt;strong&gt;number of Twitter followers&lt;/strong&gt; - Is your activity actually generating useful traffic? Monitoring the conversion rate of social traffic to a revenue event would compliment this greatly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conversion rate of key pages&lt;/strong&gt; instead of &lt;strong&gt;time on site&lt;/strong&gt; – Can you optimise your content, page design or traffic sources to get more customers rather than simply having visitors spend more time on your pages?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actionable metrics tend to be very specific and work best when focused on in small quantities – too many and their impact will be diluted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##So how can vanity metrics ever be useful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be clear, a solid set of actionable metrics is the foundation of any good dashboard. But at the end of the day, dashboards (especially TV dashboards) are there to serve people. And because people have different expectations, mixed levels of interest in data and varied perspectives, devoting a little space on your dashboard to vanity metrics can go a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In what ways can vanity metrics help?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting your team engaged with your dashboard:&lt;/strong&gt; Because of their feel-good-factor and often fast-moving nature, vanity metrics can be great for generating interest in a dashboard throughout the day, and therefore give added visibility to your other (hopefully) actionable metrics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s almost an emotional beginning. We all have a number we would be happy if it went up. At the heart of it, it’s that kind of emotional curiosity that motivates and keeps people engaged. Don’t necessarily start with the most important thing, don’t try to find the perfect metric. Think about what gives you an emotional reaction and it starts to get fun that way. Once it’s fun then it just starts rolling.” - Max Keeler, Chief Projects Officer, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fool.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Motley Fool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivating people:&lt;/strong&gt; Some metrics, like number of customers, can have a motivational effect, even if they aren’t actionable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In the lobby of our office we knowingly display some vanity metrics. Facebook Likes, for example, are largely non-actionable and don’t mean a lot day-to-day. But displaying that we have over 1 million followers shows anyone walking past that we’re an authority in our field.” – Todd Wolfenberg, CEO, &lt;a href=&quot;http://yogainternational.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Yoga International&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Providing useful background information:&lt;/strong&gt; Even if they can’t directly impact decision making, some vanity metrics are useful to know regardless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I put our top ten best-selling products on our TV dashboard. Now my colleagues can tell me what they are because they see the list every day and they know where to focus their efforts.” - Linus Larsson, Global Online Traffic Manager, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thule.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Thule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating context for PR, stakeholders and customers:&lt;/strong&gt; Although superficial by themselves, metrics such as revenue, number of customers and headcount can be useful for giving people outside of the company context around the company.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fostering transparency:&lt;/strong&gt; Having a radically open culture is increasingly important to &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/blog/buffer-transparency/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a number of companies&lt;/a&gt;, and making certain vanity metrics freely available on a dashboard can support a drive to be more transparent.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Early on, we came close to running out of money and I wanted to communicate some urgency to the rest of my team and be transparent with the situation we had on our hands. I put a dashboard up in the entrance to the office that people had to physically walk around to get to their desk, and on it was just one visualization showing the amount of cash we had in the bank. Seeing that every day when coming to work was a stark reminder to everyone that this is reality, not Silicon Valley!” - Jindou Lee, Founder and CEO, &lt;a href=&quot;http://happyco.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;HappyCo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Summary: How to use vanity metrics sensibly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure you have a foundation of solid actionable metrics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recognize when you are handling a vanity metric&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be very clear on what your purpose is for sharing it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never let a vanity metric direct actions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How have you successfully used vanity metrics? Let us know in the comments below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=”typeform-widget” data-url=”https://simon406.typeform.com/to/pr80Vq” data-transparency=”100” data-hide-headers=true data-hide-footer=true style=”width: 100%; height: 450px;” &amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &lt;script&gt; (function() { var qs,js,q,s,d=document, gi=d.getElementById, ce=d.createElement, gt=d.getElementsByTagName, id=&quot;typef_orm&quot;, b=&quot;https://embed.typeform.com/&quot;; if(!gi.call(d,id)) { js=ce.call(d,&quot;script&quot;); js.id=id; js.src=b+&quot;embed.js&quot;; q=gt.call(d,&quot;script&quot;)[0]; q.parentNode.insertBefore(js,q) } })() &lt;/script&gt; &amp;lt;div style=&quot;font-family: Sans-Serif;font-size: 12px;color: #999;opacity: 0.5; padding-top: 5px;&quot; &amp;gt; powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typeform.com/examples/?utm_campaign=pr80Vq&amp;amp;utm_source=typeform.com-8113383-Pro&amp;amp;utm_medium=typeform&amp;amp;utm_content=typeform-embedded-poweredbytypeform&amp;amp;utm_term=EN&quot; style=&quot;color: #999&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Typeform&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">“Vanity metrics are dangerous.” - Eric Ries, The Lean Startup</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pipedrive’s co-founder Timo Rein reveals how they segment goals to keep focus [Podcast]</title><link href="http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-pipedrive-timo-rein-podcast/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pipedrive’s co-founder Timo Rein reveals how they segment goals to keep focus [Podcast]" /><published>2017-05-17T08:03:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-17T08:03:00+00:00</updated><id>http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-pipedrive-timo-rein-podcast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-pipedrive-timo-rein-podcast/">&lt;p&gt;For this episode, we spoke with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/timorein/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Timo Rein&lt;/a&gt;, Co-Founder of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pipedrive.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pipedrive&lt;/a&gt;. Pipedrive is simple sales management software for any business focused on growth. Their customers are small businesses all over the world, across languages and industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a simple and useful product early on was key to Pipedrive’s success. Other contributing factors were focusing on support early on, breaking down goals, and hiring for character-fit. Here’s a quick company overview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Founder experience: &lt;em&gt;7 years&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team size: &lt;em&gt;250 team members&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customers / Revenue: &lt;em&gt;Over 50,000 customers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company founded: &lt;em&gt;2010 (7 years old)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Business model: &lt;em&gt;SaaS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hear their story in the full episode:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/323075506&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Like this episode? To be notified when the latest episodes are available, subscribe to Secrets for Scaling on &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/geckoboard&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/secrets-for-scaling/id1178675789?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Episode highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remove the easiest roadblocks preventing viral growth&lt;/strong&gt;. In Pipedrive’s case, this was language and localization for their product. They focused on making the product available and localized in the beginning, allowing them to quickly grow globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify your influencers as early as possible&lt;/strong&gt;. Timo said that effective marketing when you first launch is about getting your product into the hands of the right people early on. Pipedrive focused on the best tech incubators and accelerators with portfolio companies who would benefit from it in each market they served.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambition and conviction are key when doing something new and scary&lt;/strong&gt;. For Timo, building a self-service product was scary because, before Pipedrive, he had over 12 years experience in hands-on enterprise sales. It was terrifying to build something that people didn’t need him for. But market trends pointed in the direction of SaaS and he had the confidence it would work out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on quality support from the beginning&lt;/strong&gt;. This was key for Pipedrive. One of their co-founders worked solely on customer support for two years before hiring for the role. This gave the founding team an intimate knowledge of how their customers interacted with the product and the type of support people they needed to hire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Segment your goals into easily digestible areas&lt;/strong&gt;. Timo splits the company’s goals into three pillars: 1) organization/team, 2) product, and 3) business/revenue. Defining short and long-term goals for each, this breakdown creates definition and meaning around the company’s goals for the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find the right routines (or processes)&lt;/strong&gt;. Timo says the most important thing when setting goals was to find the right routines for their team. This includes how they as a company talk about goals, where they talk and set them, what the cadence is for setting and tracking them, and how each individual team sets and tracks goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take a holistic approach to measuring success&lt;/strong&gt;. Pipedrive tracks the typical KPIs for a SaaS business: website visits, trial signups, MRR, churn, etc. However, Timo says the real driver of the business is measuring the whole Pipedrive experience - support, sales, and the product. This is done through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/learn/kpi-examples/marketing-kpis/net-promoter-score-nps/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Net Promoter Score (NPS)&lt;/a&gt;, as well as some manual analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Always ask yourself “Do you have enough focus?”&lt;/strong&gt;. Timo says this is an ongoing question for the company, along with, “do we have too many goals?” and “are they still somewhat vague?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicate only the most critical goals&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if you have seven goals for your team this year, Timo recommends picking two to three to communicate with your team to maintain focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can’t repeat your goals and vision enough&lt;/strong&gt;. Timo learned that “you have to repeat, repeat, and repeat the things you want to see happen.” Even today, this is a work in progress for the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustaining a company culture comes down to hiring&lt;/strong&gt;. Timo says you have to find the right fit because you’re not going to influence a candidate to be a different person once they join. That’s why Pipedrive has a pretty rigorous hiring process with at least three or four interviews. More importantly, they define the right competencies for each role and the right character in everyone. A culture doesn’t come from talking about it, it comes from each individual being themselves and finding people who align with the company’s character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask character questions when interviewing&lt;/strong&gt;. During the culture-fit interview when hiring, Timo looks for people who get more energy from their work than they spend. He wants people with high standards for themselves no matter what other people say. He looks for people who are teachable and able to control their ego – people influenced by their team and not only worried about their career moves. To determine if candidates fit this profile, he asks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you feel the work you’re doing is what you’re meant to do? - do you have an emotional connection to it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you feel about other people in the world? - what do you dislike about other people?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you think makes you difficult for others to work with?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define your fit and create your own questions&lt;/strong&gt;. Timo suggests reflecting on what makes a person a fit for your culture and developing your own questions based on your company’s values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Record your problems and make sure they’re visible to relevant team members&lt;/strong&gt;. Communication is not only important for aligning around team goals, it’s also key for ensuring your team knows which issues to focus on. When problems arise, Timo advises to record them, discuss them with your team, and keep them in front of your faces until they’re solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you been enjoying episodes of S4S? We’d appreciate a &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/secrets-for-scaling/id1178675789?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;review on iTunes&lt;/a&gt;. It only takes a minute. Cheers!&lt;/em&gt; ✌&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For this episode, we spoke with Timo Rein, Co-Founder of Pipedrive. Pipedrive is simple sales management software for any business focused on growth. Their customers are small businesses all over the world, across languages and industries.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Facebook’s “7 friends in 10 days” got everyone confused about correlation and causation</title><link href="http://geckoboard.com/blog/how-facebooks-7-friends-in-10-days-got-everyone-confused-about-correlation-and-causation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Facebook’s “7 friends in 10 days” got everyone confused about correlation and causation" /><published>2017-05-10T14:44:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-10T14:44:00+00:00</updated><id>http://geckoboard.com/blog/how-facebooks-7-friends-in-10-days-got-everyone-confused-about-correlation-and-causation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://geckoboard.com/blog/how-facebooks-7-friends-in-10-days-got-everyone-confused-about-correlation-and-causation/">&lt;p&gt;With easy access to more data than we’ve ever had before, it’s important we don’t make logical errors that lead us to false conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We’ve noticed that people who share during their trial tend to be more likely to convert. How can we get more people to share during their trial?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It looks like people who use the product at least twice in their first week have higher levels of retention. How do we get more people to come back?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“People who use this feature end up subscribing to more expensive plans. How do we get more people to use it?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever started a project based on an observation like this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the face of it, these seem like data-informed insights: we’ve noticed a link between user behavior and a desirable outcome, and want to increase the behavior to increase the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not quite as simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While each of the observations is factually correct, there’s an implicit assumption that’s been made before posing the question. Let’s look at the first example in more detail:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’ve noticed that people who share during their trial tend to be more likely to convert.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool. Seems reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How can we get more people to share during their trial?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danger!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are we asking this question? Because we want more people to convert, of course. But in asking this question, we’re making a big leap: we’re assuming that getting more people to share during their trial &lt;em&gt;will directly lead&lt;/em&gt; to more people converting. We’ve assumed &lt;em&gt;causation&lt;/em&gt; — that A causes B to happen — where the data only gives us &lt;em&gt;correlation&lt;/em&gt; — that there is a relationship between A and B. This is known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Post_hoc_ergo_propter_hoc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;post hoc fallacy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding and proving causality is hard, so in all likelihood if we were to use this observation as evidence to embark on a project where the measure of success is “increased sharing during trial” we won’t see a corresponding increase in conversion. In fact, assuming that we do manage to increase sharing, we’d see the strength of the relationship between sharing and conversion &lt;em&gt;decrease&lt;/em&gt; if there’s not a causal relationship between the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been guilty of making this mistake early in my career, and I continue to hear it from others to this day. It’s a problem that seems to have become more prevalent as data collection gets easier and tools to analyze it become more accessible to everyone. It can be easy to get caught up in the excitement of thinking that you’ve uncovered a pattern and that because it comes from &lt;em&gt;data&lt;/em&gt; it must be objectively true. But the ability to step back and analyze the situation is crucial to avoid making this kind of mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-it-worked-for-facebook&quot;&gt;Why it worked for Facebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook’s ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://ryangum.com/chamath-palihapitiya-how-we-put-facebook-on-the-path-to-1-billion-users/&quot;&gt;7 friends in 10 days&lt;/a&gt;’ is probably the most famous example of the type of observation I’ve described above. However, contrary to what I’ve suggested, by doubling down on improving this metric Facebook &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; see massive success. How can this be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To recap, the social media giant found that people who reached 7 friends in 10 days were far more likely to remain engaged with the product than those who didn’t. So they asked the question “How can we get more people to reach 7 friends in 10 days?”, and spent a lot of time and effort increasing the number of people who met this condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superficially, this set-up looks similar to the ones that I trashed above, but there’s a crucial difference: there’s a causal explanation as to why Facebook’s observation might cause the behavior they want to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about the implications of reaching 7 friends in 10 days: it means that your Newsfeed is likely to have fresh cat videos, baby photos, and fake news each time you log in, several times a day. It’s &lt;em&gt;directly linked to the progress&lt;/em&gt; that Facebook is trying to help users make: to never be bored while stuck in a queue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you could argue that I’ve just provided an after-the-fact explanation. Was the team at Facebook thinking about whether there was a causal explanation? Who knows! Even if they had, how would you be able to distinguish between a genuine cause and a compelling story that makes logical sense but has no basis in reality?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s here where cold, hard numbers play their part. By forming a hypothesis — for example, that helping more users to reach 7 friends in 10 days will result in a corresponding increase in engagement — then carrying out experiments to impact this metric and measuring the result, you can verify whether or not there’s any causal link between the two, or whether you’ve overlooked a more fundamental issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-better-source-of-inspiration&quot;&gt;A better source of inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, it’s important to remember that our role as product builders is to help people &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/jobs-to-be-done-introduction/&quot;&gt;make progress in their lives&lt;/a&gt;. Once you understand what success looks like for your users, it’s much easier to get a feel for whether a pattern in the data is likely to be causal or correlative. Data is important —and  necessary! — to help us to assess the success and impact of our efforts, but rarely do great features that users love come from asking “How can we make people do X more?”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">With easy access to more data than we’ve ever had before, it’s important we don’t make logical errors that lead us to false conclusions.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tyler Barstow of Vinyl Me Please on how to not be a jerk manager when growing a business [Podcast]</title><link href="http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-tyler-barstow-vinyl-me-please-podcast/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tyler Barstow of Vinyl Me Please on how to not be a jerk manager when growing a business [Podcast]" /><published>2017-05-09T07:50:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-09T07:50:00+00:00</updated><id>http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-tyler-barstow-vinyl-me-please-podcast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-tyler-barstow-vinyl-me-please-podcast/">&lt;p&gt;For this episode, we spoke with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tylerbarstow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tyler Bastow&lt;/a&gt;, co-founder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vinylmeplease.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vinyl Me Please&lt;/a&gt; - a monthly record subscription club. Founded in an apartment as a side project in 2012, VMP has been through textbook growing pains. They’ve learned big lessons in focus, communication, and product development along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tyler shares how their customers have grown up with them, how they align their team around the vision, set and track goals, and how they’ve learned to lead and manage founder stress without bumming their team out. Hear the whole story here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/321742741&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Like this episode? To be notified when the latest episodes are available, subscribe to Secrets for Scaling on &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/geckoboard&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/secrets-for-scaling/id1178675789?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Episode Highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your early adopters won’t always be the biggest part of your target market&lt;/strong&gt;. Your first customers won’t always be your most valuable. Your product will evolve as you learn more about the market and automate tasks to scale. Some of them will stand by your side, others will go. It’s just one of those things you have to accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Honest and transparent communication is essential for customer retention and loyalty&lt;/strong&gt;. When issues arise regarding delivery or bugs, it’s best to communicate what happened, why, and what actions you’re taking to make it right. Be open and honest with your customers. In Vinyl Me Please’s case, they couldn’t get a record out by Christmas and would’ve gone bankrupt trying to get another out. They had to tell their customers this directly and empathetically. As a result, they lost a few customers but are still here and growing today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can’t repeat your goals enough&lt;/strong&gt;. At Vinyl Me Please, different teams own areas of the business with each member owning their own tasks. The entire team then gets together every two weeks to report progress, give ideas, and share how they can help each other. The leadership team re-shares their vision, goals, and progress against those goals. They encourage areas of the business that aren’t moving as fast as they’d like and celebrate those that are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To set goals, break your vision up into practical action items&lt;/strong&gt;. For team alignment, Vinyl Me Please outlined what they want to be as a company in practical terms. The leadership team asked themselves and the team: “what does the best damn record club ever look like?” Then asked, what does support, content, marketing, etc. look like for the best record club?” Those answers end up being their goals for the year or quarter. They then arrange those goals in a way that makes people accountable to accomplish them and feel free to shift direction as they’re learning along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try to get from the abstract to the tangible as quickly as possible&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s what Vinyl Me Please has done. They create timelines and structure around the practical goals mentioned above so they can answer the questions, “was this a good idea or no?” and “what returns is this idea getting us?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s easy to feel like progress is being made when it’s not&lt;/strong&gt;. Tyler reflected, “If you can’t put actionable steps to what you’re trying to accomplish, then what you’re trying to accomplish as a business isn’t going to happen or isn’t possible. At that point, it’s not a business, it’s a thought experiment you’re doing on someone else’s dime.” This is similar to SpaceX’s “mission to metrics” concept that Mark Chung of Verdigris &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-verdigris-mark-chung/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shared in his interview&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set expectations that will push your team but aren’t unreasonable&lt;/strong&gt;. Tyler says it’s good to set big goals but to make the tasks around them simple and digestible for your team. That way, they’ll know how they’re making an impact. With a defined scope of work, they’ll be focused and motivated. &lt;em&gt;(At Geckoboard, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/okrs-objectives-and-key-results/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;use the OKR framework&lt;/a&gt; to apply this concept.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being a “jackass” isn’t an effective managing tactic&lt;/strong&gt;. Tyler says that effective managers listen to their team’s thoughts without saying a lot. He suggests being careful not to critique too much or to shut down ideas before trying them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accept that you don’t know as much as your team - don’t bum your employees out&lt;/strong&gt;. Tyler said, “I tend to assume now that I don’t know nearly as much about something as the person doing it every day, which is so obvious. But sometimes when people start companies, part of their need to control something, to have input and drive direction on everything, is really just micromanaging and bums people out.” He added, “I think in general, good entrepreneurs don’t bum their employees out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know that your stress is not caused by your team&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s easy to take your stress out on your team because you work with them every day. But your stress most often isn’t caused by them - it stems from the pressure you put on yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business is a human enterprise, after all&lt;/strong&gt;. Tyler reflected, “One thing to keep in mind is that business is fundamentally a human enterprise. I think one of the annoying things about the quest for perfectionism is that perfection is not a human quality and it’s not ever going to be. Adjust to the fact that you’re going to make mistakes, your team is going to make mistakes, your customers are going to make mistakes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To be a successful entrepreneur, you need to work on yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. He added, “Getting to a place where you stop projecting your problems on the people you work with, your product, and your customers is as close to perfection as you’re going to get. A lot of the work you do as an entrepreneur ends up being work you do on yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tyler suggests trying therapy, prioritizing your personal health, and finding resources that help you confront yourself in a mature and constructive way, whether that’s mentors, books, etc. Having a company is stressful, but it’s important to remember that other people have stress too. In Tyler’s experience, the antidote to feeling alone is to get rid of your ego and open up to people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books and podcasts mentioned&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ego-Enemy-Ryan-Holiday/dp/1591847818?tag=ryanholnet-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ego is the Enemy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Ryan Holiday&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Daily-Stoic-Meditations-Wisdom-Perseverance/dp/0735211736?tag=ryanholnet-20&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Daily Stoic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Ryan Holiday&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acast.com/howididit/scottbelsky-howafounderbuilta-150millioncompanyandturnedhalfofhisemployeesintomillionaires&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Scott Belsky: How a founder built a $150 million company and turned half of his employees into millionaires&lt;/a&gt; [Podcast]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you been enjoying episodes of S4S? We’d appreciate a &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/secrets-for-scaling/id1178675789?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;review on iTunes&lt;/a&gt;. It only takes a minute. Cheers!&lt;/em&gt; ✌&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For this episode, we spoke with Tyler Bastow, co-founder of Vinyl Me Please - a monthly record subscription club. Founded in an apartment as a side project in 2012, VMP has been through textbook growing pains. They’ve learned big lessons in focus, communication, and product development along the way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Build better dashboards by iterating</title><link href="http://geckoboard.com/blog/build-better-dashboards-by-iterating/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Build better dashboards by iterating" /><published>2017-05-05T11:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T11:01:00+00:00</updated><id>http://geckoboard.com/blog/build-better-dashboards-by-iterating</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://geckoboard.com/blog/build-better-dashboards-by-iterating/">&lt;p&gt;Great designs rarely come about by accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind almost every successful product or piece of software, a large amount of work goes into prototyping, testing, gathering feedback and optimising in an effort to make the end product deliver as much value as possible to the end user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a useful dashboard for your team is no different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Geckoboard we’ve seen countless examples of business dashboards made by our customers over the years, and one thing we’ve realised is that great dashboards are an ongoing collaboration between whoever decides what the objectives are for a team, and the team themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re thinking about refreshing the dashboards your company uses already, or you’re just starting to plan what metrics to track, here’s how bringing an iterative design mindset to the process can ensure the dashboard you and your team are looking at day-to-day is always relevant and makes a direct impact on your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Build&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most critical step of the process is to get started. Your aim should be to have something to show to your team that can start generating real feedback on what’s useful to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A useful idea to bear in mind is that of a ‘&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startuplessonslearned.com/2009/08/minimum-viable-product-guide.html&quot;&gt;Minimum Viable Product&lt;/a&gt;’ (MVP). What dashboard can you make that will allow you to learn the most from your team with the least amount of effort? Less is more, and at this stage you shouldn’t be worrying about building a fully fleshed-out dashboard before sharing it with your team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve already tracked metrics using another tool or spreadsheet in the past, the first metrics you add to your dashboard may be obvious. However, if this is the first time you’ve sat down and thought hard about what makes sense to track, the process may feel like guesswork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to cast aside any assumptions or fears and get to the point where you can show something to the rest of the team that starts a conversation. This is how you kick-start the process of refining what’s on your dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/iterative-design-diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;iterative-design-diagram&quot; /&gt; 
&lt;em&gt;Don’t get bogged down with tracking down data or adding lots of metrics. An MVP can be as simple as one metric or a mockup &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/dashboard-creation-the-post-it-note-approach/&quot;&gt;made with Post-it notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Learn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s extremely unlikely you will have created a perfect dashboard on your first attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s therefore important to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2013/02/designing-great-feedback-loops/&quot;&gt;gather useful feedback&lt;/a&gt; from others so you can make informed changes to your dashboard. Elements to consider changing include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What metrics are on the dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The visualizations and timeframes used&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The layout of metrics on the dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The priorities given to certain metrics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Titles and annotations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How metrics are divided between different dashboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweaks to any one of these elements can make a massive difference to how useful your dashboard is to others, so as a dashboard creator it’s critical to make informed choices about what direction to take things in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some ways to open up a conversation with your team about what’s useful include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display it prominently on a screen:&lt;/strong&gt; Start using your dashboard ‘in the wild’ day-to-day and see what feedback you get organically from your team. You might be surprised at some of their suggestions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set up a mini ‘user-test’:&lt;/strong&gt; Set time aside to bring your team together to run through your dashboards and discuss what’s useful or could be improved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuously ask questions:&lt;/strong&gt; Understand whether the metrics on your dashboard are valuable and driving appropriate action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you able to look at this and take action based on what the metric is showing?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do these metrics help us work towards our goals?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there a clearer way to represent this?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is there anything we can remove from the dashboard to make it clearer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Adjust and repeat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you gather feedback, make changes that address the issues you’ve identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there are a lot of fundamental changes, remember: A dashboard that fails to prompt action and doesn’t focus your team is not useful to anyone, so don’t be afraid to start again from scratch and try a different approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few rounds of feedback, you should be much closer to having a dashboard that’s useful for your team. But this is not the end of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Businesses are in a constant state of flux, and the metrics on your dashboards will likely need to adapt as your team develop new ideas about which metrics are impactful, as your business goals evolve and the people on your team change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay open to feedback, help others think critically about their metrics with the questions above, and you’ll be best-placed to keep your dashboards relevant and actionable going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/the-dashboard-iteration-process.png&quot; alt=&quot;the-dashboard-iteration-process&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Summary: How to start iterating today&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build a minimal version of your dashboard to get in front of your team as early as possible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you already have dashboards, start gathering feedback from your team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask questions that will uncover what’s important, what’s missing, and what can be removed, and make appropriate changes to your dashboards&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take time to read up on the subject of useful metrics and using dashboards. The Lean Analytics &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2p99hqJ&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/lean-analytics-workshop-alistair-croll-and-ben-yoskovitz/&quot;&gt;free course&lt;/a&gt; are recommended.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;KEEP GOING!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do you incorporate feedback from your team into your dashboards? We’d love to hear your tips in the comments below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;resource-boxed&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;title-tab&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;category&quot;&gt;Alejandro Pérez - CEO, Komet Sales&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;How one SaaS company CEO uses iterative design thinking&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kometsales.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Komet Sales&lt;/a&gt; is a 51-person SaaS B2B platform that allows a company to manage everything around running an import and wholesale flower operation.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Dashboard building is an ongoing process but you’ve got to get started – getting started is 90% of the job done. It’s like setting up a garden. You do some heavy lifting and then you start pruning to maintain everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It helps to imagine the dashboard as valuable real estate. If every metric you add is going to cost you a hundred bucks, which ones would you put up? Having this in your mind will make you much more selective. My mistake when I started building dashboards was to get excited and think ‘I’ve got to fill it up!’. My first dashboards looked like Christmas trees and created total confusion because there were too many things for people to look at. It’s much better to start small and build up slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of vanity metrics on our first boards. For example, number of boxes of flowers moved every day. It’s interesting to know as a reference, but it’s not going to help us do a better job. To get the team to understand vanity metrics and help them iterate on their dashboards, I asked a lot of questions like ‘How is the number of cases we’ve closed in the last 3 months useful? How is this going to help us achieve our goals? How is this going to help us serve our customers better today?’ If the customer asks how they’re going to get a better service and they can look at numbers on a dashboard that actually impact them, then that’s useful to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dashboard iteration is a process that keeps on going forever and ever. When we were five people and then 20 and now 51, the metrics changed because the whole business is different. The same metrics we used five years ago or two years ago or a year ago don’t necessarily work today. Your best past business practices can become your worst future business practices. The world, and your business, is moving so fast that you need to be willing to make changes at the flip of a dime.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=”typeform-widget” data-url=”https://simon406.typeform.com/to/WSooSa” data-transparency=”50” data-hide-footer=true style=”width: 100%; height: 450px;”&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;script&gt;(function(){var qs,js,q,s,d=document,gi=d.getElementById,ce=d.createElement,gt=d.getElementsByTagName,id=&quot;typef_orm&quot;,b=&quot;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/share.typeform.com/&quot;;if(!gi.call(d,id)){js=ce.call(d,&quot;script&quot;);js.id=id;js.src=b+&quot;widget.js&quot;;q=gt.call(d,&quot;script&quot;)[0];q.parentNode.insertBefore(js,q)}})()&lt;/script&gt;&amp;lt;div style=&quot;font-family: Sans-Serif;font-size: 12px;color: #999;opacity: 0.5; padding-top: 5px;&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Great designs rarely come about by accident.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Insights from the top two startup books recommended by founders</title><link href="http://geckoboard.com/blog/insights-top-two-startup-books-recommended-by-founders/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Insights from the top two startup books recommended by founders" /><published>2017-05-04T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-04T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://geckoboard.com/blog/insights-top-two-startup-books-recommended-by-founders</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://geckoboard.com/blog/insights-top-two-startup-books-recommended-by-founders/">&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, we interviewed over twenty founders and CEOs of online businesses to understand their most pressing challenges and the resources they’ve found most helpful. Among the questions was one regarding the most impactful books they feel every other founder should read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two books that were by far most recommended were &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Hard-Thing-About-Things-Building/dp/0062273205/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1493313186&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+hard+thing+about+hard+things&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Hard Thing About Hard Things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Ben Horowtiz and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/High-Output-Management-Andrew-Grove/dp/0679762884&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;High Output Management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; by Andy Grove. With such high founder recommendations, we wanted to share some of the key takeaways and actionable questions from both of these books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##The Hard Thing About Hard Things
&lt;em&gt;Building a Business When There Are No Easy Answers&lt;/em&gt; by Ben Horowitz, Cofounder and General Partner of Andreessen Horowitz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/hard-thing-about-hard-things-ben-horowitz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hard-thing-about-hard-things-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Hard-Thing-About-Things-Building/dp/0062273205&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The hard thing isn’t setting a big, hairy, audacious goal. The hard thing is laying people off when you miss the big goal. The hard thing isn’t hiring great people. The hard thing is when those “great people” develop a sense of entitlement and start demanding unreasonable things. The hard thing isn’t setting up an organizational chart. The hard thing is getting people to communicate within the organization that you just designed. The hard thing isn’t dreaming big. The hard thing is waking up in the middle of the night in a cold sweat when the dream turns into a nightmare.” - Ben Horowitz, The Hard Thing About Hard Things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####At a glance
In this brutally honest book, Ben Horowitz chronicles his story from first-time founder to going public to selling Opsware (formerly Loudcloud) to becoming a venture capitalist.This book is packed with insights, but perhaps the most valuable lesson could be summarized in one sentence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Founding and growing a company is really hard with no easy answers or guaranteed recipes for success, but the experience and bits of advice from other founders who’ve been there before (and screwed up) can help with the hard things.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike many formulaic business books, this one isn’t about the silver bullet to success or how to avoid screwing up. It’s about what to do when you do screw up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####Key Takeaways 
&lt;strong&gt;The struggle is real as a founder.&lt;/strong&gt; The struggle itself isn’t failure, but it can lead to failure. The key is to not quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Perhaps the most important thing that I learned as an entrepreneur was to focus on what I needed to get right and stop worrying about all the things that I did wrong or might do wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take care of the people, the products, and the profits - in that order.&lt;/strong&gt; Taking care of the people is certainly the hardest of the three, but if you don’t do it, the other two won’t matter. Build the kind of “good” company where people enjoy coming to work. Ironically, this doesn’t matter when things go well, but it can be the difference between life and death when things go wrong. Things always go wrong, so it always pays to create a good company where the team is treated well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be honest and direct in your communication, especially with difficult news.&lt;/strong&gt; Founders often lean towards one of two extremes: becoming too positive (always looking on the bright side, often taking things too personally) or rationalizing bad news (not taking things personally enough). The team deserves to know the true reality of the company. Hiding facts erodes trust and can actually dampen morale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A healthy company culture encourages people to share bad news. A company that discusses its problems freely and openly can quickly solve them. A company that covers up its problems frustrates everyone involved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know whether you’re in &lt;a href=&quot;http://a16z.com/2011/04/14/peacetime-ceowartime-ceo-2/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;peacetime or wartime&lt;/a&gt; and lead accordingly.&lt;/strong&gt; One is focused more on expanding and maximizing current opportunities while the second is laser focused on completing a critical mission. These two different settings require drastically different management styles and approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;blog-newsletter-signup inside&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;newsletter-signup-head&quot;&gt;Can we send you a short weekly email with lessons learned from other founders scaling their business?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;form action=&quot;//geckoboard.us1.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=f8c11c17753d5c653c8d22b3d&amp;amp;id=d7a449ccce&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; id=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&quot; name=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&quot; class=&quot;validate form-wrapper&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; novalidate=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;email&quot; value=&quot;&quot; name=&quot;EMAIL&quot; class=&quot;required email&quot; placeholder=&quot;Your Email Address&quot; id=&quot;mce-EMAIL&quot; /&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Subscribe&quot; name=&quot;subscribe&quot; id=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe&quot; class=&quot;button&quot; /&gt;&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you have to let people go, be quick, candid, and present.&lt;/strong&gt; Sharing candidly with the whole team the reason for the layoff (company/market/product performance vs individual performance) helps soften the bad news and builds trust with the remaining team members. Use decisive language (i.e. avoid wording like “I think…” or “We might…”). The sooner people are told, the better. Then be present to answer questions and talk to people once you’ve given the news. The people who remain need to know that you’re there, you care, and the company is moving forward.
####Questions to spur action 
Here are a few questions to help you process and implement the ideas in this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What would I do if the worst case scenario happened?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Don’t stop at asking “what is the worst case scenario?” Rephrasing the question to something actionable is a much better alternative than just accepting your worst case scenario. The simple existence of an alternative, plausible scenario is often all that is needed to keep hope and your company alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“People always ask me, “What’s the secret to being a successful CEO?” Sadly, there is no secret, but if there is one skill that stands out, it’s the ability to focus and make the best move when there are no good moves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What am I not doing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
The things you are not doing are the things you should actually be focused on. Instead of reviewing what you’re currently doing and trying to marginally improve those things, think about the things you’re not doing in the market but could or should be. What does the market need, but doesn’t realize yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If our company isn’t good enough to win, then do we need to exist at all?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Every company must fight for its life at one point or another. If you find yourself running when you should be fighting, it’s time to ask this tough question and answer honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How can I ensure team members receive adequate and ongoing training?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
“Being too busy to train is a moral equivalent of being too hungry to eat.” The primary reasons people leave a job (aside from economics) is because of a lack of guidance and development, they aren’t learning or developing new skills, and they aren’t receiving any feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“…even with all the advice and hindsight in the world, hard things will continue to be hard things. So, in closing, I just say peace to all those engaged in the struggle to fulfill their dreams.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##High Output Management
By Andrew Grove, Former Chairman and CEO of Intel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/high-output-management-andy-grove.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;high-output-management-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/High-Output-Management-Andrew-Grove/dp/0679762884/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1493676956&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=high+output+management&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####At a glance
Andy Grove doesn’t waste any time explaining the process and structure for improving your performance (or ‘output’) as a manager. Written on the premise that everything can be modeled in a repeatable production process, this book breaks down the universal components and shows how to track and achieve high-quality results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He provides practical advice for key managerial duties such as structuring a team, making decisions, reviewing performance, setting objectives, motivating employees, and more.
####Key Takeaways 
&lt;strong&gt;Managers leverage their time to increase output with three primary duties: 1) information gathering and giving, 2) decision-making, and 3) nudging or following up.&lt;/strong&gt;  Done well, these activities lead to relevant and timely training, effective delegation with follow-up, and efficient workflow. Done poorly, these activities delay decisions, create unnecessary interruptions, and result in unfinished or dropped tasks. Having between six to eight direct reports is the ideal team size for a manager to be most effective with these tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;”A manager’s output = the output of his organization + the output of the neighboring organizations under his influence.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make progress toward long-term plans by setting short-term &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/okrs-objectives-and-key-results/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;objectives and key results (OKRs)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Remember that planning is an integral part of any managerial role and involves studying the environment, knowing where you are, and finding a hypothetical path to meet demand. Objectives (sub-goals for long-term plans) and key results (measurable milestones indicating progress toward objectives) should be cascaded throughout the company to keep everyone focused and working towards the overall, long-term plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Measurement against a standard makes you think through WHY the results were what they were.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manage team members based on their level of “task-relevant maturity.”&lt;/strong&gt; There’s not a single best management style since what is most effective depends on who you’re managing. “Task-relevant maturity” (TRM) is an individual’s degree of achievement-orientation (i.e. their readiness to accept responsibility, training, and experience). High TRM requires minimal direction and increases managerial leverage while low TRM needs task-oriented direction specifying what, how, and when. But be careful not to “…confuse people’s task-relevant maturity with their general competence.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Because it is easier to monitor something with which you are familiar, if you have a choice you should delegate those activities you know best.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training and motivation are a manager’s job.&lt;/strong&gt; Providing scheduled, ongoing training is the highest impact activity a manager can do to increase the output of the organization. When a manager provides training for their direct reports instead of outsourcing it, the instruction is more relevant and expectations are clearly defined for each role. This sets employees up for success and makes it easier to evaluate performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Insufficiently trained employees, in spite of their best intentions, produce inefficiencies, excess costs, unhappy customers, and sometimes even dangerous situations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level (be direct and honest), listen, and leave yourself out of performance reviews.&lt;/strong&gt; When you write and deliver employee evaluations, include only what is directly relevant both with praise and criticism. Then listen carefully to ensure the individual thoroughly understands what was shared and why. Keep any of your challenges, fears, or insecurities out of the review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####Questions to spur action 
Here are a few questions to help you process and implement the ideas in this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.geckoboard.com/blog/leading-lagging-or-lost-how-to-find-the-right-key-performance-indicators-for-your-sales-team/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;leading and trending indicators&lt;/a&gt; should you track to ensure you hit your objectives?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Avoid focusing exclusively on activity and instead track leading indicators - metrics that evaluate input and predict output. These indicators are even more impactful when paired with the right trending indicators (sometimes called lagging indicators) - metrics that show output over a specific time period (e.g. week, month, year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What decision is needed? By when? Who should be consulted? Who decides? Who ratifies or vetoes? Who needs to be informed?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
The biggest challenge to good decisions is that people don’t speak their mind freely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you say “yes” to this project, what other projects will you be saying “no” to?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
“Remember too that your time is your one finite resource, and when you say “yes” to one thing you are inevitably saying “no” to another.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What small problems should you be fixing right now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
“A common rule we should always try to heed is to detect and fix any problem at the lowest-value stage possible.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is this meeting necessary? If yes, what format will be most efficient and effective?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; 
Broadly speaking, there are two main types of meetings: process-oriented and mission-oriented. The first type (process-oriented) is typically scheduled and focused on information exchange. This includes one-on-ones, staff meetings, and operation reviews. The second type of meeting (mission-oriented) is ad hoc, focused on a specific output and requires a champion to moderate the meeting efficiently. Be clear at the outset what type of meeting you’re having to best leverage everyone’s time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you want to work and continue to work, you must continually dedicate yourself to retaining your individual competitive advantage.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Earlier this year, we interviewed over twenty founders and CEOs of online businesses to understand their most pressing challenges and the resources they’ve found most helpful. Among the questions was one regarding the most impactful books they feel every other founder should read.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lessons from Pramod Dabir of West Agile Labs on minimizing technical debt while moving fast [Podcast]</title><link href="http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-pramod-dabir-of-west-agile-labs-podcast/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lessons from Pramod Dabir of West Agile Labs on minimizing technical debt while moving fast [Podcast]" /><published>2017-05-02T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-02T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-pramod-dabir-of-west-agile-labs-podcast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://geckoboard.com/blog/secrets-for-scaling-pramod-dabir-of-west-agile-labs-podcast/">&lt;p&gt;For this episode of Secrets for Scaling, we chatted with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/pdabir/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pramod Dabir&lt;/a&gt;, Co-Founder and CEO of &lt;a href=&quot;http://westagilelabs.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;West Agile Labs&lt;/a&gt; - a global digital design and development partner. With offices in San Francisco, Ukraine, Pakistan, and India, Pramod is focused on ensuring that each office is running smoothly, aligned around their vision, and communicating effectively across teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick company snapshot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Founder experience: &lt;em&gt;6 years&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team size: &lt;em&gt;150 team members&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customers / Revenue: &lt;em&gt;40 clients&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company founded: &lt;em&gt;December 2012 (5 years old)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked to Pramod about what you can do early on for smooth growth, how to align a distributed team around a vision, how to build a sustainable MVP, and more. Listen to the full episode here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/320515671&amp;amp;color=ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Like this episode? To be notified when the latest episodes are available, subscribe to Secrets for Scaling on &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/geckoboard&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Soundcloud&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/secrets-for-scaling/id1178675789?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Episode highlights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hiring operations people early on is crucial for smooth growth&lt;/strong&gt;. Structure has been key to West Agile Labs’ operations. That’s why they hired operations leads on the global and local scale early on. Pramod and his partner run operations at their headquarters in San Francisco. Another senior person works with each office on a strategy for key hires and operational activities. They also have a head of global operations, and an office lead for each location. These people manage the day-to-day operations and are responsible for developing and maintaining the culture of each office which varies by location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hire junior roles with potential for senior-level positions&lt;/strong&gt;. West Agile’s senior leadership grew into their positions. They built the trust and autonomy needed in a leadership position by starting out in a junior position early on. They already embodied the company’s culture and knew how to communicate it with their direct reports by the time they were promoted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust your gut when hiring - a bad hire has a huge impact&lt;/strong&gt;. If you or your team members have any doubt that a person isn’t a fit, trust your intuition. Don’t force a hire you have doubts about, especially if you feel like you’re on a time crunch. Don’t rush it, hold out for the right person. Pramod reflected on the impact of bad hires, “It’s amazing how much a bad hire can affect you, the business, and other people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set the vision and let your team define their actions&lt;/strong&gt;. Pramod and his leadership team set the direction, vision, and overarching goals for the company. The team then defines what they think is the best approach for meeting those goals and what they can get done. The leadership team provides guidance and support, and the team defines what the deliverables, timelines, and expectations are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage tools to stay connected&lt;/strong&gt;. West Agile Labs has a tool stack to foster collaboration among their distributed team. They use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teamwork.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Teamwork&lt;/a&gt; to manage and log their time, and its threaded conversations to replace email. They use Google Drive for document collaboration, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bitbucket&lt;/a&gt; for code collaboration, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invisionapp.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Invision&lt;/a&gt; for design collaboration. Finally, they use &lt;a href=&quot;http://slack.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; for general back and forth communication with clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An MVP (minimum viable product) should have a solid foundation with minimal features&lt;/strong&gt;. Taking the time to build the core of what you need and limiting the bells and whistles will result in a product that solves your core problem and is ready for sustainable business growth. Pramod often sees founders build too much for an MVP and spend too much money on it. He believes founders should allocate equal funding to marketing and sales as they do to the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balance technical debt and pushing features fast&lt;/strong&gt;. Pramod suggests being mindful about how quickly you want to move vs. how much you’d like to avoid returning to cleanup mode. He understands it’s difficult to avoid all technical debt. If you’re building for speed, it’s important that the core of the product is solid and clean. Then you can go back and cleanup features later - just make sure you allocate time for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engagement metrics are most important post-launch&lt;/strong&gt;. Try to focus on people who care about your product after launch. Ten highly engaged users are more valuable long-term than one hundred who are not. With engaged users, you’ll get better feedback and build a better product. Once identified, focus on other users who have a similar need or use case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t get caught up with the small things&lt;/strong&gt;. Finding someone to help with the little tasks has always been a challenge for Pramod. Learn to delegate the day-to-day tasks that are preventing you from stepping back and thinking about the business strategically. Trust in yourself that you’ve hired the right people and learn to let go as you grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have you been enjoying episodes of S4S? We’d appreciate a &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/secrets-for-scaling/id1178675789?mt=2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;review on iTunes&lt;/a&gt;. It only takes a minute. Cheers!&lt;/em&gt; ✌&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For this episode of Secrets for Scaling, we chatted with Pramod Dabir, Co-Founder and CEO of West Agile Labs - a global digital design and development partner. With offices in San Francisco, Ukraine, Pakistan, and India, Pramod is focused on ensuring that each office is running smoothly, aligned around their vision, and communicating effectively across teams.</summary></entry></feed>